this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at se - radio net se radio is
brought to you by the I Triple E
Computer Society I Triple E software
magazine online at computer org slash
software for software engineering radio
this is Elena Salinas this episode was
recorded at coop Con in Austin Texas
cop-con is the largest kubernetes
conference to date here I talked with
Nicole Hubbard Nicola is an architect at
WP engine where she focuses on building
container based infrastructure
automation and helping teams deploy
their applications prior to that she
worked at Rackspace on projects to power
their cloud servers and on building
software to automate the management of
their data centers nicole has over 10
years of experience developing software
and has a passion for building micro
services that manage infrastructure you
are giving a talk here at koukin and
it's titled scaling to five thousand
unique kubernetes deployments and how
you're doing this we're gonna be talking
about this today but first to give a bit
of context I want you to just describe
what WP engine is yeah so WP engine is
the leading WordPress digital experience
platform and we work with over 70
thousand customers from a hundred and
thirty countries and we power over three
hundred thousand WordPress installations
on our platform three hundred thousand
three hundred thousands and over five
percent of the web visits at least one
WP engine powered site every day ok so
this is really good because we get an
idea of the scale of the product let's
talk about managed wordpress hosting
can you describe what this is so our
co-founder Jason Cohen started wpengine
because back in their late 2000s he was
starting his own blog and he was having
a lot of difficulty running that and so
he actually started WP engine as a
simple hosting company and then we've
expanded on that to add additional
offerings things around security and
making the platform highly performant
and then also lastly we added our
support layer so and over the years
we've been building on that platform
adding things like analytics and
personalization for our customers that
helped them power their digital
experience WordPress is open source
wordpress.org so I'm really curious why
are people willing to pay to have free
software managed for them so WordPress
is free like a puppy is free and you
know you you get the puppy for free but
you still have to feed the puppy and
take it to the vet and get shots and
WordPress has maintenance needs just
like anything else so just because you
can download a zip file with PHP code
doesn't mean that its skills doesn't
mean that it's secure by default and
there's a lot of maintenance around
keeping it up to date following security
releases and those types of things so
when I start getting into a bit of the
technical details of WP engine
can you describe its architecture sort
of the the main components at a higher
level first yeah so our main components
are we have what we call so we run on
top of a virtual infrastructure do you
mean virtual machines virtual machines
yes and so in that virtual machine we
run everything we need to power the
sites on that machine so we have nginx
and varnish and my sequel and all the
storage for those machines there we also
have an another offering that's our
clusters and it's very similar the
difference is we're able to run numerous
web heads and those run are in
and Apache processing to do the PHP
processing and our varnish workers and
then we actually pulled the database and
file storage off unto separate servers
that are then shared I see and just
before this we were talking about how
people are willing to pay to have their
software managed what are some of the
problems WP engine itself again just to
give the context before we get into the
migration I want to understand what is
it solving security so companies turn to
WP engine to help with security ensuring
that their sites online we have an
award-winning support team that's
available 24/7 to answer any questions
that come up and so those are the huge
advantages that we offer what are some
examples of applications and customers
of WP engine yeah so one of our
customers is AMD's developer central web
site is hosted with us they were facing
some problems their CDN solution did not
allow them to host files greater than 25
megabits and they were constantly
uploading files larger than 200
megabytes so they had to turn off their
CDN and this caused huge performance
problems for them so they worked to
migrate to WP engine to help solve those
another one of our customers is the CMAs
so the Country Music Association and
they actually just recently had their
large event a couple weeks back where
and so we work with them very closely to
ensure that they were able to keep their
site online during their award ceremony
and keeping updates as the award winners
were announced during your time as
architects one of the projects you've
been focusing on is migrating to
kubernetes and from what I understand
and from what you just mentioned is it's
built on top of virtual machines
originally can you describe what this VM
infrastructure consists
and what its purpose is yeah so the VM
infrastructure consists of engine X
varnish Apache my sequel and some other
tools we run internally to help manage
stuff the first step in our migration
into kubernetes
is to actually move the PHP processing
off of the VMS and into the kubernetes
cluster but we've before we get to that
let's see let's just focus a little bit
on this virtual machine so prior to the
migration the what used to be the
current state of things so these virtual
machines what were they being used to
mentioned they host Apache and things
like that okay yeah so the virtual
machines hosts all of our customer sites
most of the sites live on one of the
virtual machines unless they're in one
of our clustered offerings
what were they indication the indicators
that showed it's time to move to
something else or that maybe we don't
want to stick around with this virtual
machine infrastructure so one of the
largest indicators that we saw with our
VMs were around the utilization we had
very low utilization numbers as a whole
when we took the aggregate for all of
them below 40 percent so most of our
virtual machines were sitting around
very bored but they would have
occasional spikes where they would use
all of the resources for each of the VMS
but those never seem to occur at the
same time and so we thought there has to
be a way we can get better utilization
is this an issue because you're saying
40 percent is being utilized and this
cost money is that what the issue is
they're just sitting there yes so we
leverage AWS and Google for most of our
infrastructure and so we pay per core
and memory that we provision and for
those to be sitting around not being
utilized and means we're spending money
on infrastructure we don't need
okay and was this the initial
infrastructure the virtual machines or
was there something prior to this
virtual machines so we've always been on
virtual machines the way they've looked
and the way they've been shaped has
changed over the years
but they've always been very similar to
what we have now and this project that
you've been working on is well first of
all you at the beginning said there's
70,000 customers I think and you're
working on moving 60,000 customers from
virtual machines to kubernetes did you
decide to move particular customers
first like is there a step where you're
saying oh it's better if we move X first
and why later so we have different
levels of plans that we offer to our
customers so we have our personal plans
we have our premium plans business plans
enterprise plans so with the migration
we've started with our personal things
these are generally people's personal
blogs so we will roll that out to a
small percentage of them first and
validate no problems and then as we
continue in the rollout we gradually
start including the additional plans
going up the SAC to some of our larger
customers is it because they have
specific characteristics with their
usage of it a lot of times it's due to
the risk profile that those sites are
willing to tolerate so before we we
wanted to keep the risk of our larger
sites to a minimum as much as possible
and ensure that we were able to catch
any problems before we had major sites
on it okay so here you're talking about
moving just one low risk tier of your
real customers do you also do first like
some test accounts and then just pretend
you're migrating then they're not real
customers but they look a lot like real
customers so we have a bunch of internal
accounts that we use some of these
provide and
Meishan for our support teams we have
public-facing sites that we host one of
those being our support garage and so we
actually will are working to move those
sites and we'll complete those before we
move customers so we like to validate
things with internal accounts before we
ever put customers on them to ensure
that we've got the vast majority of any
problems that are going to come up
before it impacts the customer ok and
this problem is the reason we're talking
about this is because it's not unique to
wpengine there are lots of companies
that go through these types of
migrations and like we're talking about
moving up test accounts first and then
internal accounts then real customers
from a specific tier and you are moving
60,000 of them out of 70,000 first are
their customers with unique systems that
will have to remain in in the virtual
machine infrastructure is there such a
thing as oh because of your type of page
that you're hosting you should always be
never too much so for our initial
rollout we are going to continue to
allow our enterprise customers to run on
their VMs mostly because they have
larger workloads they already have web
servers that scale up and down based on
the requests that they have coming in so
we're gonna continue with that for those
customers but for all the others who run
on single node vm's they'll be migrated
into kubernetes okay how big is a
wordpress instance so it varies based on
the installation of work WordPress so
they can range from a couple megabytes
all the way to gigabytes depending on
how many assets you have how many
plugins you've installed how larger
database is based on the post you've
made and the comments on your site and
all of that so we have things ranging
all the way from
in the megabytes 10 20 Meg's all the way
up to numerous gigabytes and essentially
you're hosting a wordpress instance
right yes okay how many would you say
you can serve from a single virtual
machine due to some of the limits that
we've ran into around our security
modeling we're limited to only a couple
hundred per machine on our virtual
infrastructure that we use today mm-hmm
let's talk a bit more about this virtual
machine infrastructure what are the
technical advantages that virtual
machines provide playing server
applications so in we get to leverage
the cloud which is a huge advantage for
us versus having to buy Hardware it
allows us to scale up our infrastructure
as customers purchase things and without
you know having a server hardware cost
which was the initial motivation of why
a lot of companies moved to this right
because they they had their own hardware
or maybe they were not even creating a
business because they couldn't afford
the hardware and things like that right
yeah okay let's start talking a bit
about this migration from virtual
machines to kubernetes do you know more
detail about these cost benefits in
addition to the utilization yeah so as
we move into kubernetes our target is
around a 70% CPU utilization and so
we're hoping that this is able to
actually provide us a significant
reduction in our infrastructure cost
just from moving into kubernetes let's
do a quick recap of what kubernetes is
is this is what we're gonna be talking
about later on can you explain what
kubernetes is yeah so kubernetes is a
container orchestration tool and so what
that means is we're able to tell
kubernetes what the state of our cluster
should be and it will continuously run
and ensure that things are in the crowd
state using reconciliation loops what do
you mean by state so the state is which
things should be running like we want
three instances of this application
running in the cluster and we want ten
instances of this application and so we
schedule those in and it then
coordinates that and spreads it across
all their hardware so is the state about
the cluster or the application because
when I first heard this state I meant I
understood like stayed running state
stopped state restarting so in this case
it's mostly the state of the application
and the desired state of it so by desire
state it would be oh now I need four
instances of the application and and
there used to be one okay one of the
things you mentioned about kubernetes is
this an orchestration to all four
containers these are not virtual
machines can you explain the difference
between these two so when you start a
virtual machine you get a full operating
system with all of the libraries and all
of the software and packages that come
in an operating system so this gives you
your NIT system you're logging via
syslog and Linux and then you've got SSH
so that you're able to log in and then
once you have so after you have all your
basic system processes you then get to
start running your processes on top of
that whereas when you run inside of a
container
you've got your operating system still
that's running on the host node but when
you start the container the only things
that are actually starting are the
application that you've defined in it
and it also provides an isolated
environment for your application to run
in so say you have two applications that
require different versions of Ruby with
the same some of the same packages but
different versions of them and things
like that that can start to be a little
bit of a pain
manage all on the same server in a
virtual machine in a virtual machine
yeah and but when you stick those into a
container they get their own isolated
runtime environment and it provides that
isolation allows them to have only
exactly what they need okay so you said
virtual machine you're getting a full
copy of the operating system so every
time so as essentially you're getting a
new computer to put it in simple terms
yeah and four containers there's one OS
that you specify called the host and
inside of it you run multiple containers
and in each container you specified the
specific environment that you need for
your application to run for example in
the same machine you can have a
container running Python 2.7 and another
one that's Python 3 right correct ok
let's start talking about this migration
from virtual machines to kubernetes what
are some of the other disadvantages of
having customers and virtual machines in
addition to this cost related problem is
there anything else like about the OS
and installing things so one of the
other downsides that we face is as we
continue to grow the number of virtual
machines we have continues to grow for
example if you look at my talk it says
5000 unique this is because when I
submitted it we had just over 5,000
virtual machines now we've actually
surpassed 6000 virtual machines and that
was in a short amount of time was it a
couple of months it was over yeah less
than a year ok and as we continue to
grow when we have to deploy changes out
to all of those servers it takes longer
and longer and the management of those
servers so we have to manage you know
kernel upgrades packages on the servers
that have to be upgraded and all of
those
and that provides a lot of overhead is
this growth attributed to new customers
or just existing customers getting more
views of their raps or both
so it's both we have existing customers
who continue to grow with us and upgrade
to even larger plans that resulted in us
building larger infrastructure for them
and then adding new customers as well
okay what would you say the main
motivation of this migration was one of
our main motivations was to simplify the
management of our infrastructure okay
first I would have guessed the cost
related what that's a good answer
the business is all about the cost
savings the engineering departments all
about the simplification so there's both
benefits if I talk to somebody in that
area they would say the cost but
simplifying infrastructure is good too
you have the customers on wpengine
that you know you're gonna move to
kubernetes how do you structure this
migration plan yeah so we've written
some software that goes through and
looks at some of the plugins that are on
all of the installations on what do you
mean plugins so WordPress supports
installing plugins so these range from
things that add simple functionality or
potentially say a different commenting
system instead of the built in one all
the way to things like WooCommerce which
allows you to provide ecommerce through
WordPress so we look one of the biggest
risk is the plugins for the migration so
we look through the plug-ins that are
installed on the sites and we build out
the migration plan for plugins that we
know don't have any problems and we'll
work to transition those sites first and
then ones where we're unsure we do some
testing to make sure those plugins work
and then we slowly start moving those
installations over
and so we're entirely confident on those
plugins as well
in the example that you mentioned of a
plug-in is let's say I have my own site
it's a blog it comes with a default wait
for people to write comments about my
post so a plug-in would be a different
way to write comments on my site yeah
okay why did you mention these plugins
are a risk one of the largest parts in
this migration is we're moving from
Apache with mod PHP into PHP fpm and in
that migration we lose the ability to
use HT access files and there are some
plugins that heavily rely on that as we
found as we started this migration can
you explain what the htaccess file is
yeah so an HT access file allows you to
set configuration values for Apache for
the directory that you're in and the sub
directories port so one of the largest
uses of it is to set let to create
rewrite rules and these allow you to
change the way that the URL gets sent to
the backend to actually be processed and
then you can also do things like
redirects and some other you know
configuration values okay so what you're
saying is plugins provide this risk in
this case because they're using a
different version of PHP that relies on
this it's because of the use of htaccess
yes okay so that's the first step of the
migration plan to analyze the website or
blog and find this dependencies that are
the plugins consider dependencies yeah
you could consider them dependencies so
you'll find them and then flag them if
there's a plug-in that you know cannot
be my greater than you yeah that's the
first step that's the first step
okay what comes next in the migration
plan so during the actual transition
when we bring the site online in
kubernetes what we do is we do a quick
validation of the site before we
transfer it to ensure the site is
working as we expect and then we
transition the site to performing the
PHP processing inside of kubernetes and
then we do another validation to ensure
that it's still responding the same way
so this is once you've migrated you do a
first validation or where's the first
validation happening
so the first validation happens right
before we migrate them so we validate it
and then we migrate it and then we've
out well
we check it then we migrate it and then
we validate that it's the same what are
some of those checks
so first validation so for the most part
it's loading the homepage of the site
and ensuring that it loads without any
errors okay so you're checking the page
loads without any errors before you have
done anything to the correct okay if
something if something about the site is
not working correctly already we don't
want to make that worse by potentially
by migrating okay and then what did you
say comes after this first validation so
after that we migrate them and then we
do that exact same validation step again
to ensure that the site's loading
correctly being processed in kubernetes
does this validation needs to be
automated or is it enough yes we wrote
automated scripts around it and those
provide the ability for us to move an
entire virtual machine with a simple
command
what technology was used for those
validation scripts so they are done in
Python okay because first I thought this
would be like there's these tools for
testing websites where selenium is one
of them and what you can do is it
automatically launches a browser you you
see it being launched and rendering the
page and things like that so yeah so
those are really good tools in this case
we actually so we're also using go for
this we've written us internal tool that
we use and go that can actually go
through and hit all the sites and so the
Python script actually wraps around that
so the ghost script does the actual
validation of the site okay in this
validation are you looking at network
traces or no response error codes we're
specifically looking at response codes
and the page the actual body of the page
to ensure it returned correctly and you
don't look at the UI what it looks like
no not in this case okay and for the
body
it's the HTML body of the page what are
you validating there that specifically
that it's loading correctly and that
there's actually a body there okay let's
see what are the specific pieces that
need to move from a B n BM to core
binaries so in our first step in the
migrating into kubernetes the specific
piece that were migrating is the PHP
processing so we're moving from running
Apache on the virtual machine to running
PHP fpm with a go wrapper around it in
kubernetes what did you say is the first
the regional PHP version or what was the
name PHP fpm that's the new one right
that's the new one Oh the original was
Apache
and is there a significant difference
between those two for the most part no
the largest difference is the htaccess
file that I mentioned earlier but
besides that they both run PHP code
almost the same way so it's very little
difference okay but why wouldn't you use
the same one so with Apache you have to
configure configuration files for every
site and point it to the directories and
then there's a lot of work we have to do
and we leverage app armor to provide
security so that one site can't access
the files on another site and that we're
able to restrict certain things that we
need to restrict for security reasons in
the case of PHP fpm were able to start
the workers for it in isolated
namespaces and then mount the files for
that request for the installation in
real time as they come in so that they
only have access to those files whereas
that wasn't something we could easily
accomplish with apache okay so would you
say PHP fbm has sort of wrapped all this
notion of config options to an extent
yes a lot of its we wrote a lot of
custom go code that handles the
responses as they come in before passing
them to PHP fpm and so since PHP fpm
uses a fast CGI connection we're able to
forward the request to it over that what
do you mean by fast cgi so fast CGI is
the implementation are the interface
that you use to talk to it it's a PHP
fpm so just a recap part of the
motivation is that you're not using the
same PHP yes because of this config file
is and there's a lot of hockey work it
seems like to secure it and make sure
you don't talk to who you're not
supposed to talk to him so so it greatly
simplifies engineering
to move to PHP fpm yep exactly okay
as part of this migration when you're
moving VMs to kubernetes how do you
store customer specific data for example
is it volume mounts or how does this
work
so what we've done for the initial stage
is we leveraged NFS to mount the files
from the virtual machine into the
kubernetes pods can you explain a little
bit about NFS yeah so NFS provides you a
way to share a file system across the
network and so it basically allows you
to mount that filesystem and work with
it just like you would any other set of
files what have been some of the
benefits of moving to kubernetes because
like we mentioned is container
orchestration tool right so beyond the
simplification for management and cost
savings which are two huge benefits
we've also been able to start leveraging
kubernetes for our internal applications
so some of our internal micro services
and we get a lot of value there in the
way that we're able to deploy things
like monitoring services and logging
services we're able to get automated
processes that configure those and read
the logs and ship them to our logging
destinations and things along those
lines so it has increase of speed of
which you deploy instances it does allow
significantly faster deploys as well and
as we continue moving forward with
building smaller micro services that are
only responsible for one thing that
allows us to deploy those in a
significantly faster and C icd way
versus our older more monolithic
projects which had to be deployed out to
6000 VMs and we were actually were only
able to deploy those once a week
okay do you have an idea of the cost
comparison of running kubernetes versus
VMs so we're looking at somewhere
between 40 and 50 percent cost savings
as we continue to move into kubernetes
between 40 and 55 zero okay wow that's
pretty good
have there been unexpected costs along
the way of this migration though like
yes you get cost savings but maybe there
are some costs for doing this
not really we've ran into a few things
we're like we just kind of
underestimated the amount of resources
we would need but nothing huge does the
customer know there's this migration
happening maybe not in migration terms
but do they know something's going on so
as part of our communication with our
customers we're giving them a heads up
that over the you know we give we're not
telling them specifically when they're
being moved but we do tell them that
coming up in the near future your site
will be transitioned to a new back-end
but hopefully if everything goes
according to plan it's completely non
impactful for the customer yes and what
do you need to do to make sure it's non
impactful do for example is it running
at the same time in the VM and as in
kubernetes how does a do guarantee that
it'll be seamless to the customer so for
the first week after we migrate a site
into kubernetes we continue to run
Apache on the VM and if for any reason
were unable to make the request to
kubernetes or if for any reason a
customer starts reporting problems we're
able to switch them back to the Apache
back-end and to allow everything to
process just like it was before
so it sounds like at the beginning you
you're gonna have both infrastructures
fully running right just for a brief
period of time okay is that time
determined based on if customers are
reporting things or is it set in stone
like for one month we're gonna run both
of them so the goal is it's two weeks
but if customers are reporting things
will obviously extend that have there
have been migrations that have failed
not currently we we've only moved a
handful well
we've moved our internal stuff and we've
done some burnin and so we have a couple
hundred sites that are running on it now
and we've not experienced any problems
and even if some of them fail well you
have this rollback plan right yeah okay
so it's looking pretty good as what
you're saying that's good and let's see
and the duration of the migration does
it depend on who you're migrating like
how big the site is and things like that
yes since we're only moving the PHP
processing and we're not actually having
to move the files or anything along
those lines it actually the size of the
install doesn't matter in this case
so what happens is we spin up the
infrastructure in kubernetes to do the
PHP processing for that set of installs
and then once that's running we
reconfigure those sites to then process
there and it's completely transparent to
the requests coming in and everything's
handled what are some of the technical
aspects of container research management
and kubernetes or do you do you have to
manage is there resource management
so kubernetes allows you to control the
resources of the individual containers
so you're able to limit the CPU in the
RAM and so we have limits that we've put
in place for each of those to help keep
those where we need them to be
and is this automatically handle as
you're scaling like those kubernetes
take care of that
so kubernetes won't automatically set
your resources but as long as you've set
the limits you can then use what's
called a horizontal pod autoscaler and
that will be able to automatically scale
your application up and down and do you
specify their range yeah you can give it
a min and a max let's talk a bit more
about scaling and infrastructure in the
description of your talk I saw that you
mentioned most organizations only need
to run a couple of deployments of their
application in kubernetes what do you
mean by this so what I mean is when you
look at you know a service that a
company writes they deploy it into
kubernetes and they usually run a
production version maybe a staging and a
QA and a testing and some dev versions
but overall you're not having to deploy
the same application over a hundred
times you're talking maybe 10 to 20
instances of it whereas in our case we
have to deploy thousands I see so this
is because of the scale of WP engine so
what you're saying in general the
majority it's not this big scale yeah
that and you're able to use you'll still
have a large scale but it's scaling one
application really large whereas since
we have to provide for you know over
300,000 WordPress installs we have
numerous installations and in this cases
why is it straightforward to deploy to
kubernetes is it because it's just
clicking a button or just a simple
command so there's a lot of tools out
there that help with deplaning the
kubernetes helm is one of the big ones
and so how makes it really easy to
deploy an instance of your application
and even
when you need to deploy a staging
version and a production and or dev
versions it makes that process really
easy for you but when you start having
to deploy even a hundred of those you're
having to manage a hundred different
config files for each of those that you
provide to helm and that starts to
become a little cumbersome inhale inside
out yeah so then what are you doing that
case is there another tool that you use
or so what we did we actually wrote a
tool that we've made open-source called
lost Ramos and what it does is it
leverages kubernetes has the concept of
custom resources and these allow us to
define any they represent any object
that you want and so we're able to
define our virtual machines as a custom
resource and then run a helm deploy for
each of those virtual machines and are
you managing kubernetes in your own
infrastructure or through a cloud
provider so we're leveraging cloud
providers I'm specifically Google and
AWS and we're leveraging Google's gke
offering ok that's interesting because
some of the people that I talk about
they they're either AWS Google or only
asher is there a reason why you're using
two of them are you doing things in one
of them that you don't get in the other
one not really no it's not that one of
them provides us something the other
doesn't it's mostly about the
availability of regions and what some of
our customers demand from and what to
have for their provider
so one provider might be in other
regions not the other one isn't yeah
technically they're the very similar is
just about this region's correct okay
what are the reasons why you would need
to simultaneously deploy 5,000 unique
instances of your applications so for
our case it's specifically around the
scale we're at and being able to deploy
and continue to migrate into kubernetes
and so to make that process as simple as
we could it was easier not to completely
overhaul all of our infrastructure in
the first stage so but to continue to
leverage the infrastructure we had in
place and start pulling pieces out of it
and what do you mean by unique instances
for example is there a case where you're
deploying simultaneously 5,000 not
unique instances of your application
potentially that would be something that
could happen in our case what we're
deploying is 5,000 instances of the same
application so it's our custom PHP
processing application and the only
differences are some environment
variables that held the process where
the files are located so which of the
VMS that it's responsible for serving so
that's what the unique stand for stands
for in this case yep okay what are some
of the challenges of having an
application that needs to be available
worldwide so there's a lot of unique use
cases that you start to run into when
you look at worldwide availability of
applications one of them being not all
countries have the same connectivity and
when the request is coming from China
and it has to go all the way to the US
to be served that starts at a lot of
latency so trying to remove as much of
that latency
as possible and it's it's actually one
of our goals in future steps in our
migration to kubernetes
is to actually try to remove as much of
those Network hops as we can so by
making the front edge of our network for
all of our customers available worldwide
and all of our data centers so what
you're saying is to reduce that latency
is this one you have to use a CDN so
Citians can help with this so as part of
our offering we do provide a CDN that
customers can use but not all of our
customers leverage the CDN do you know
why is this because costs most say I
think it's around cost okay are there
any other challenges of having a
worldwide application well those are the
big ones those are the big ones yes and
I guess the other challenges would fall
more under the customers application
right if it's worldwide
we'll make sure you support different
languages and your images don't have
text in only one language and things
like that right yeah so a lot of those
challenges fall onto our customers
actually managing their sites but since
we don't have any control over what's
actually on the sites that's entirely up
to the customer what is needed to manage
kubernetes are skills the first thing
you mentioned earlier is do not do it
directly on kubernetes but find tools
like helm and things like that is there
anything else that you need to manage it
at scale modeling is extremely important
we leverage Prometheus within our
kubernetes clusters to be able to get
metrics and data out and then generate
alerts what sort of metrics do you get
with Prometheus so it's able to talk to
our applications and read any metrics
that they're exposing to it so anything
from average request time
to slowest request to number of requests
anything along those lines so these are
things that use specifying the
application yeah you get to specify them
for your applications okay and well I
guess can you explain a bit of what
prometheus is is it a wraparound
coordinated so Prometheus is part of the
CN CF it was the second project accepted
by the CN CF and it provides a tool that
will go out and talk to your application
and hit a metrics endpoint so it scrapes
the app and it saves all of those into a
time series database that you're then
able to query okay and do you use a
separate tool to visualize this data
yeah so we leveraged crow fauna to
actually be able to query Prometheus and
you guys play graphs okay lots of pretty
dashboards and how do you normally
decide on which tools to use like does
it depend on what it costs is it open
source so we went the route of Griffon
and Prometheus specifically Prometheus
because it was able to handle the needs
of the infrastructure that we have we
run into problems sometimes where some
tools don't handle the scale that we're
at whereas Prometheus did not have that
issue we do like working with open
source tools but we're also willing to
leverage commercial offerings if they
meet our needs well Nicole thank you for
coming on the show it's been great
talking to you thanks for having me
thanks for listening to se radio an
educational program brought to you by
Triple E software magazine for more
about the podcast including other
episodes visit our website at SE - Radio
net
to provide feedback you can comment on
each episode on the website or reach us
on LinkedIn Facebook Twitter or through
our slack channel at SC radio.com you
can also email us at team at SC - radio
net this and all other episodes of SU
radio is licensed under Creative Commons
license 2.5 thanks for listening